Guide to the Irish Echo Photographs AIA.045
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Irish Echo Photographs
1925-2006
1971-2004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Irish echo
AIA.045
27.08 Linear Feet in 13 record cartons, 11 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 3 oversize flat boxes, 1 oversized flat folder, and 8 card boxes.
505 Megabytes in 92 files
The Irish Echo is a nationally circulated Irish-American newspaper published weekly in New York City since 1928. The paper covers political, social, entertainment, and sports news from both Ireland and Irish America, in addition to national and international content from the perspective of the Irish American community. This collection consists of photographic prints, transparencies, photo negatives, and photographic slides used to produce the Irish Echo. Common subjects documented within this collection include Irish and Irish American politicians, society events, sporting events, musical groups, arts and cultural events, as well as visiting celebrities and dignitaries.
Historical Note
The Irish Echo is a nationally circulated ethnic newspaper published weekly in New York City.The paper was founded in 1928 by Charles Connolly, a native of County Monaghan. In 1955, Patrick J. Grimes, a native of County Offaly, purchased the paper, which was subsequently run by members of the Grimes family for the remainder of the twentieth century. In 2002 the newspaper was sold to Irish businessman Sean Finlay, who sold it to the Belfast Media Group in 2007. Máirtin Ó Muilleoir is the current CEO and publisher.
The paper covers political, social, entertainment, and sporting news from both Ireland and Irish America, with a robust classified section targeted at domestic help, legal notices, and construction employment. News stories featured in most daily newspapers also often received coverage, from the perspective of the Irish American community.
Sources:
Claire Grimes, "History of the Irish Echo," New York Irish History 8 (1993-1994)
A Salute To 75 Years of the Irish Echo (NY: Irish Echo, 2003)
James V. O'Connor, Resisting the Melting Pot through Ethnic Newspapers: History and Function of the Irish Echo (Ph.D., Temple University, 2008)
Patrick Farrelly and Eamon Lynch, "Censorship at the Irish Echo," The Blanket: A Journal of Protest and Disssent, 20 June 2003, online at http://indiamond6.ulib.iupui.edu:81/censorshipie.html
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
The Irish Echo's photo morgue was donated to the Archives of Irish America when the newspaper moved its editorial offices from midtown Manhattan to lower Manhattan in the summer of 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2007.045. Further additions to the collection were received by the archives in 2012.
Sponsor Note
Detailed processing and encoding for this collection was made possible by a grant from the Irish government's Department of Foreign Affairs, Emigrant Support Programme.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of photographic prints, transparencies, photo negatives, and photographic slides used to produce the Irish Echo, but is not limited to images published in the newspaper. The majority of the images in the collection were submitted by the Irish Echo staff and contract photographers, although some photographs were sent to the paper by unsolicited individuals. Photographers for the Irish Echo featured in this collection include John Bourke, Peter Dolan, Kevin Kennedy, Tom Matthews, and Michael O'Rourke. Also represented, particularly in Series V: Artists and Series VI: Film, Television, and Theatre, are publicity photographs from a variety of sources, including public relations firms and production studios.
The majority of photographs featured in the Irish Echo's photo morgue document Irish and Irish American people and communities, news events, and subjects throughout the greater New York City area. The collection also features numerous American and international figures and organizations interacting with Irish American communities. Politicians, society events, sporting events, schools and youth organizations, musical groups, arts and cultural events, as well as visiting celebrities and dignitaries are among the most common subjects documented throughout the collection.
The files are particularly rich in images related to Irish immigration and American assimilation processes during the latter half of the 20th century. Numerous images of Irish and Irish American communities and their leaders provide visual documentation of the ways in which these populations negotiated their dual identities and transmuted cultural traditions. Furthermore, the materials featured in this collection provide insight on editorial decisions regarding the prioritization of news, specifically as it pertains to content.
The majority of the collection consists of images taken in the United States, with the exception of Series II, which documents tourism, business, politics, sports, and various other topics specific to Ireland. Additionally, there is no distinction made within Series V - VII between Irish and American origins. For example, images in Series V: Artists, include photographs taken of American artists in Ireland as well as of Irish artists in America. Due to the multifaceted nature of the collection's images, individual events, people, or subjects may appear in multiple locations throughout the collection or within a single series.
Many of the prints show permanent evidence of their use, including crop marks, retouching by highlighting or shading, or other manipulation of the image. These marks are part of the record of a working newspaper and have been preserved as part of the history of the Irish Echo's photograph morgue. With the advent of digital photography and other technologies, the quantity of photos included in the collection declines beginning in the late 1990s, continuing steadily downward to 2004, which represents the latest date in the collection.
Related Archival Materials
Archives of Irish American Newspaper and Periodical Collection (AIA 004)
New York Public Library microfilm copy of Irish Echo(ZY 86-164, 1935-present with significant gaps before 1950)
Arrangement
The collection is organized into seven series, five of which have been further arranged into subseries. All series and subseries are arranged alphabetically. The arrangement of the materials is as follows:
Series I: Irish America, 1936-2004
Subseries I.A: Organizations: General, 1937-2004
Subseries I.B: Politics, 1966-2001
Subseries I.C: Subjects, circa 1930-1936, 1967-2004
Subseries I.D: Sports, 1936, 1951-2001
Series II: Ireland, 1959-2004
Subseries II.A: Tourism, 1957-2003
Subseries II.B: Business, 1964-2003
Subseries II.C: Politics, 1959-2004
Subseries II.D: Sports, 1975-1996
Subseries II.E: Subjects, 1919, 1969-2002
Series III: United States, 1940-2004
Subseries III.A: Business, 1977-2002
Subseries III.B: Politics, 1940-2006
Subseries III.C: Sports, 1970-2004
Subseries III.D: Subjects, 1970-2003
Series IV: The Irish Echo Staff, 1971-2004
Series V: Artists, circa 1938-2004
Subseries V.A: Artists, 1925-2004
Subseries V.B: Bands, 1960-2004
Series VI: Film, Television, and Theatre, 1952, 1970-2004
Subseries VI.A: Film and Television, 1952, 1970-2001
Subseries VI.B: Theatre, 1970-2004
Series VII: Individuals, circa 1960-2004
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Irish Americans -- Societies, etc.; Irish Americans -- Music.; Irish Americans -- Ethnic identity.; Irish Americans -- Newspapers.; Irish Americans -- New York (State) -- New York -- Political activity.; Irish Americans -- New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Irish echo (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I: Irish America, 1936-2004; 7.21 Linear Feet in 2 oversized flat boxes, 3 record cartons, 4 card boxes, and 1 manuscript box
  Scope and Content Note
  This series comprises the bulk of the collection and consists primarily of photographic prints of various sizes. The contents of this series document Irish American social organizations, political figures and activities, as well as sporting events, mostly in the greater New York City area. Although some photographs in this series date back to the 1930s and 1940s, the majority of images featured in this series were taken after 1950. This series contains photographs documenting the intersection of the Irish influence on American culture, and is further divided into four subseries.
  - Subseries I.A: Organizations: General, 1937-2004
    This subseries contains photographs of various Irish American organizations and events in the United States. A large number of these photographs document County Societies' functions, banquets, and award ceremonies during the 1970s and 1980s. Other major subjects include Irish American educational institutions and charitable organizations.
    - A-Z Organizations, circa 1970-1999, undated (Oversize 22, Folder 1, Box 1)
    - American Ireland Fund (A.I.F.), circa 1970s, 1980s, 1993-1996, 2001-2004, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Irish Historical Society (A.I.H.S), circa 1970, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ancient Order of Hibernians (A.O.H.): General, 1977-1990, undated (Box 14, Folder 1-3, Box 1, Folder 4, Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Ancient Order of Hibernians: Ladies, 1975, 1987-2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ancient Order of Hibernians: National Board, 1977, 1986-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ancient Order of Hibernians: New York County, circa 1963-1990, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Boston College, 1988, 1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Brehon Law Society, 1989, 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Brooklyn Irish-American Parade, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Catholic Charities, circa 1970, 2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Cavan Association, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Celtic Care, 1989, 2000-2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Co. Offally Association, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Co. Tipperary N & B Association Scholarship Awards, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann (C.C.E.), 1987-1996, 2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Concern Charity, 1994, 2001-2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Concern Charity: "Seeds of Hope", undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Consulate Ireland/Diplomatic (I), circa 1970s - 1980s, 2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 14, Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Consulate Ireland/Diplomatic (II), circa 1970s-1980s, 2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Cooperation Ireland, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Cork Association, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Cross-Cultural Working Group, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Derry Society, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Emerald Association of Long Island, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Emerald Isle Immigration Center, 1995-1996, 2001, undated (Box 14, Folder 6, Box 1, Folder 19, Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Emerald Societies (I), circa 1960s-1989, 1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 20, Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Emerald Societies (II), circa 1960s-1989, 1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 21, Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Friendly Sons of St. Patrick, 1990, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Fordham University, circa 1970s, 1999, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - GAA Banquet, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Gaelic League Feis, 1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - The Gaelic Park Players, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Goal (Charity), 1994 - 2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Groups Unidentified (I), circa 1960s-1999, 2001, 2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Groups Unidentified (II), circa 1960s-1999, 2001, 2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Iona College (New Rochelle), 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Ireland Chamber of Commerce United States of America (I.C.C.U.S.A.), 1988-1989, 1995-1997, 2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 30, Box 14, Folder 8-10)
    - Ireland-United States Council of Commerce and Industry, 2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Irish American Athletic Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Irish American Builders Society, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Irish American Cultural Institute/Eoin McKiernan (I), circa 1970s-1980s, 1995-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Irish American Cultural Center, circa 1984-1985, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Irish American Cultural Institute/Eoin McKiernan (II), circa 1960s-1970s, 1995-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Irish American Immigration Committee, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Irish American Society of Nassau, Suffolk and Queens, NY, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Irish Arts Center (New York), undated (Box 14, Folder 11, Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Irish Business Organization (I.B.O.), 1997, circa 2001, undated (Box 14, Folder 12-13, Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Irish Language Teachers, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Irish Lesbian and Gay Organization, circa 1990s (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Irish Repertory Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Irish Counties: Antrim, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Irish Counties: Armagh, 1972, 1987-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Irish Counties: Carlow, 1995-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Irish Counties: Cavan, 1969-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Irish Counties: Clare, 1976-2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Irish Counties: Cork, circa 1970s, 1985-1989, 2004, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Irish Counties: Derry, circa 1970, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Irish Counties: Donegal: General, 1975, 1977, 1989-2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Irish Counties: Donegal: Dinner Dance, circa 2000 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Irish Counties: Dublin, 1974, 1989-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Irish Counties: Fermanagh, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Irish Counties: Galway, 1966, 1969, 1975, 1977, 1987-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Irish Counties: Kerry, 1968, circa 1975, 1985-2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 51, Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Irish Counties: Kildare, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Irish Counties: Kilkenny, circa 1970s, 1988-1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Irish Counties: Laois, circa 1970s, 1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Irish Counties: Leitrim, 1928, 1976, 1983-2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Irish Counties: Limerick, 1965, circa 1970s, 1989-2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Irish Counties: Longford: General, circa 1975-1977, 1988-1990, circa 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Irish Counties: Longford: St. Patrick's Day Ball, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 2, Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Irish Counties: Louth, circa 1970s, 1990, 1994, undated (Box 14, Folder 18, Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Irish Counties: Mayo, circa 1970s-2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Irish Counties: Meath, 1988-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Irish Counties: Monaghan, circa 1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Irish Counties: Offaly, circa 1970s-1980s, 1990, 1995-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Irish Counties: Roscommon, 1976, circa 1981, 1989-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Irish Counties: Sligo, circa 1975, 1988-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 64, Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Irish Counties: Tipperary, circa 1970, 1988-1995, 1999-2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Irish Counties: Tyrone, 1987-1989, 1996, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Irish Counties: Waterford, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Irish Counties: Westmeath, 1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Irish Counties: Wexford, undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Irish Immigration Reform Movement, circa 1970s-1980s, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Irish Institute of New York, circa 1970, 1982, 1990-2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Irish Press, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Irish Travel Agents Association, 1974, 1977, 1990, 2001, undated (Box 14, Folder 20, Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Knights of St. Patrick, 1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Molloy College, 1981, 1987, 1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Nassau Irish American Historical Society, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - New York Irish History Roundtable, 1990, 1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - New York Irish Network, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - New York University Glucksman Ireland House, 1989, 1991, 2005-2006, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Northern Ireland Investment Bill, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Out of Ireland, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Pearson's Defense Committees, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Phi Kappa Theta New York Dinner, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Pioneer Total Abstinence Association, circa 1970, 1987-1989, 1995, 2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Project Irish Outreach, 1990, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Scholarship Awards, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Sligo Men's Social & Benevolent Association, 2005 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - St. Francis College, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - St. John's University/Preparatory School, 1989, 2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - St. Patrick's Ball, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - St. Patrick's Day Parade (New York) (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Stonehill College, circa 1970s, 1989-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Tara Circle, 1994-1997, 2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 10, Box 14, Folder 21, Box 24)
    - Thomas Davis Players, 1937, 1947, circa 1950s, 1964, circa 1970s, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - TWG Ball, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - United Irish Counties Association (I), circa 1960s-1988, 1999, undated (Box 14, Folder 22-28, Box 2, Folder 12)
    - United Irish Counties Association (II), circa 1960s-1988, 1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - United Irish Counties Association (III), circa 1960s-1988, 1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 14, Box 24, Folder 23)
    - United Irish Counties: Feis, circa 1970s, 1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Wild Geese, undated (Box 2, Folder 16, Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Yiddish Sons of Erin, 1967, circa 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Subseries I.B: Politics, 1966-2001
    This subseries contains photographs of politically-affiliated Irish American causes, events, and organizations, including photographs documenting efforts made in the United States on behalf of the peace process in Northern Ireland. Common subjects include relief efforts, the 1981 Hunger Strike, and prisoner treatment with overarching themes of Irish unity and solidarity. Politicians who held office in Ireland and/or the United States can be found in Series II. Ireland: Subseries A. Politics and Series III. United States: Subseries B. Politics, respectively.
    - 1981 Hunger Strike Commemoration, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Irish Affairs, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - American Protestants for Truth About Ireland, circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Bloody Sunday Commemoration, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - British Consulate Demonstrations, 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Committee For a New Ireland, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Doherty, Pat, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Fort Worth Five, circa 1970s, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Free Joe Doherty, 1988-1989, undated (Oversize 22, Folder 2, Box 2, Folder 26, Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Gaughan, Michael: Memorial, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Human Rights, 1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Irish American Solidarity Committee, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Irish American Unity Conference, 1986, 1990, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Irish Freedom Petition Drive, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Irish National Caucus, 1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Irish Northern Aid (NORAID), circa 1970s, 1984-1988, 1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Irish Republican Army Veterans of 1916-1922, 1966, circa 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Irish Republican Club, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Irish American Issues Forum, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - McBride Principles/Solidarity, 1984, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Northern Ireland Children's Exchange (N.I.C.E.), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Northern Ireland/Irish Unity (I), circa 1970s, 1987-1995, 2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 39, Box 14, Folder 30-34)
    - Northern Ireland/Irish Unity (II), circa 1970s, 1987-1995, 2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - New York City: City Hall, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - New York City: Gracie Mansion, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - New York City: Pension Fund Investment in Northern Ireland, circa 1970s, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
    - Omagh Relief Fund of New York, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Peace Envoy, circa 1985 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Project Children, circa 1984-1985, 1999, 2000, undated (Box 14, Folder 35-36, Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Project Children: Meets Riverdance, undated (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Sinn Fein, 1995-1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - VIPs and Politicians in Groups, undated (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Subseries I.C: Subjects, circa 1930-1936, 1967-2004.
    This subseries encompasses a range of topics relevant to the Irish Echo's primary readership base: Irish Americans and Irish in America. In addition to subjects covered extensively, such as dance, festivals, and St. Patrick's Day Parades, this subseries also includes a significant number of photographs taken in historically Irish American communities throughout New York City and State. Photographs taken outside of New York are organized by state name followed by additional parenthetical identifiers whenever possible.
    - 69th Regt. NYSM (Photo Negatives), undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Abbey Tavern, undated (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Advertising: General, 1989-1994, undated (Oversize 22, Folder 3, Box 2, Folder 48, Box 30, Folder 7, Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Advertising: Real Estate Ireland, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Advertising Art, 2000-2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Arts Painting, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Arts/Crafts/Design: General, circa 1970s-1980s, 1994, 1999-2003, undated (Box 14, Folder 39, Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Arts/Crafts/Design: Kieran McGonnell, circa 2000 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Arts/Literature/Authors, 1967-1968, circa 1970s-1980s, 1993-2004, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Arts/Literature/Authors - Finn MacCool by Morgan Llywelyn, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Bagpipe Bands, circa 1970s-1980s, 1994-1998, 2004, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Banquet at Mary Willis, undated (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - California, circa 1970, 1975-1977, 1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Ceili at Gaelic Park, undated (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Charity, 1975, 1984-1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 54, Box 14, Folder 41-44)
    - Connecticut, circa 1970s-1980s, 1990-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Dance: Adult Irish, 1986-1990, 1993-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Dance: Non-Irish, 1987, 1999-2003, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Dance: Riverdance, 1994-2001, undated (Box 14, Folder 45-53, Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Dance: Riverdance (rehearsal), circa 1990s (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Dance: Step/Ceili (I), circa 1970s-1980s, 1990, 1994-2000, undated (Oversize 21, Folder 1, Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Dance: Step/Ceili (II), circa 1970s-1980s, 1990, 1994-2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Dance: Step and Ceili (Cuchullaih Irish Dancers - Dorchester, MA), 1991 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - DeValera Birthplace, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 61)